naturalproductsinsider.com 2018-02-15

# Natural Products Insider Privacy Policy | Natural Products INSIDER

**Our Commitment To Privacy**  
This site is owned and operated by Informa Exhibitions LLC ("Informa Exhibitions"). Your privacy is of the utmost importance to us. At Informa Exhibitions, we want to make your online experience satisfying and safe.

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it.

**Information You Volunteer**  
Personally identifiable information is information that can identify you, such as your full name, email address, postal address, telephone number, fax number and mobile number.

We collect personally identifiable information that you choose to provide to us when you subscribe to our magazines (either directly or through another company such as a subscription agency); sign up for email newsletters; enter a contest; participate in surveys; download premium content; register for a web site, a training course, a webcast, or tradeshow; or otherwise communicate with us. When you provide this information to us, you are no longer anonymous. We also may receive information about you from other sources and add it to the information you have provided to us.

If you purchase products or services on our website or through one of our printed forms, you may choose to provide us with your credit card information.

**Anonymous Information We Collect**  
We use cookies and other Internet technologies to enrich your online experience by managing our website and email programs. Our cookies do not contain any information, in itself, that is personally identifiable.

**Cookies**  
If your browser is set to allow cookies, we may store small amounts of information on your computer about what parts of our websites you have visited and what features you like best. We also may use cookies to identify visitors so that they don't have to re-enter their usernames and passwords. By allowing us to understand how you use our site over time, cookies can help us provide you with a better, more relevant online experience.

The cookies we store on your computer are not accessible on any other companies' websites. Some ads on our site are provided by outside companies. If these ads contain cookies, they can be accessed only by those advertisers; we do not have access to them.

Some ads on our site are provided by outside companies. If these ads contain cookies, they can be accessed only by those advertisers; we do not have access to them.

Most browsers allow you to modify your security to accept or reject cookies. You need not have cookies turned on to visit our site, but without them, your access to some areas may be limited.

**Pixel Tags**  
Informa Exhibitions may use pixel tags, also known as web beacons, clear gifs, or web bugs. Pixel tags help us improve our understanding of our web traffic and visitor behavior, as well as gauge the response to our promotional efforts. This information is non-personally identifiable and is used solely for the purposes of better understanding how our visitors use our site.

If you wish, you may disable pixel tags by setting your browser to omit images and disable JavaScript.

**Online Ad Serving**  
Informa Exhibitions uses an industry-standard, third party service to serve advertisements when you visit our sites or open our emails. This company may use cookies and pixel tags to collect non-personally identifiable information about your visits to our and other web sites to provide you with relevant advertisements about products, services, and events during your visit to our website. They can also provide us with an analysis of traffic patterns and monitor advertising efforts.

**Online Analytics**  
Informa Exhibitions uses Omniture, an industry-standard, third party online traffic analysis company to track and analyze visitor usage of our site. All information tracked by Omniture on behalf of Informa Exhibitions is non-personally identifiable. To view the privacy policy of Omniture, please go to [http://www.omniture.com/privacy/policy](http://www.omniture.com/privacy/policy). If you do not wish to allow session visitation information to be aggregated and analyzed by Omniture, you may opt out by visiting [http://www.omniture.com/privacy/policy](http://www.omniture.com/privacy/policy).

**How We Use Your Contact Information**  
We may use your contact information for any of the following reasons:

to send you notices for subscription renewal  
to provide you with information about products or services you've ordered, including web, premium content, events and tradeshows  
when you download premium content or register for a webcast on any Informa Exhibitions site, your contact information may be shared with our sponsor.  
We may also use your contact information to ask for your input to help in our research about our services, events, or products or to provide you with additional information about this site and about other Informa Exhibitions products, services, or events that we think might be of interest to you.

All promotional and research email messages you receive from us will include an option to opt out of future email communications from that particular Informa Exhibitions business.

We may also send you e-newsletters with targeted, relevant content. Each e-newsletter will provide you with an opportunity to opt out of that particular e-newsletter.

In some cases, we may send you relevant, carefully-screened offers from reputable third party businesses or organizations. Many of our customers appreciate receiving these offers because they relate to their business or occupation. However, you will always be able to opt out from receiving future third party offers. When you download premium content or register for a webcast on any Informa Exhibitions site, your contact information may be shared with our sponsor. If you do not wish to receive special offers from our sponsor, you may simply email us at [phoenix-privacy@informa.com](mailto:phoenix-privacy@informa.com) and specify which premium content or webcast you would like to opt out of.

**Information We Share with Third Parties**  
We provide contact lists to third party companies that we have employed to provide us with specialized services, including customer service, subscription fulfilment, research, statistical analysis, list cleansing, postal mailings, email and fax deployment, telemarketing, and other information services. In compliance with privacy laws, we also provide our opt out lists to those third party companies so that they can be suppressed from the communications those companies send on Informa Exhibitions' behalf. We only deal with third party companies whom we believe share our commitment to privacy and who will keep your information secure. From time to time our sponsors wish to contact our subscribers who have indicated an interest in the products, services or events publicized. If you do NOT wish to have your email address shared with that sponsor, you may contact us at the email listed below.

**Information Transfer**  
Informa Exhibitions is based in the United States of America. Any information you provide may be stored and maintained in a secure database in the United States.

In the case of a change of ownership or a merger involving Informa Exhibitions or any business that is part of Informa Exhibitions your contact information associated with that business would be one of those transferred assets.

**How We Keep Your Information Secure**  
We use reasonable precautions to prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the correct use of information.

When we contract with other companies to provide us with services, we only share personal information with those that we believe share our commitment to privacy and information security. However, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for the actions of these parties.

**Children's Privacy**  
Informa Exhibitions' web sites are not intended for use by children, especially those under the age of 13. No one under the age of 13 should provide any personal information or participate in any forums, chats, or online discussions. Minors under the age of 18 are prohibited from making purchases, including subscriptions, on our sites. Please discourage your children from providing any personal information about themselves to anyone in any public discussion areas.

**Hyperlinks**  
This site may contain links to other websites, including without limitation those websites of third parties. Their inclusion cannot be taken to imply any endorsement or validation by us of the content of any such websites. Informa Exhibitions is not responsible for the privacy practices, nor do we accept any liability in connection with the content, of such websites.

**Terms of Use**  
By using any of our websites, you consent to our use of your contact information as it is outlined in this privacy statement.

Informa Exhibitions reserves the right to access and disclose personally identifiable information to comply with applicable laws, lawful government requests and any orders of the court.

We have the right to change our privacy statement from time to time. Visitors are encouraged to review this privacy statement periodically so they have the most current information. Your continued use of this site constitutes your acceptance of this entire privacy statement.

**How to Reach Us**  
If you wish to opt out of receiving email, faxes, or phone calls from any Informa Exhibitions business, please send an email to [phoenix-privacy@informa.com](mailto:phoenix-privacy@informa.com) and specify what you wish to opt out of.
